nigo I'm trying to pull I'm trying to
pull our Athenian friends into the
conversation when reckoning with what's
the right level of intelligibility at
which to reckon this problem and the
scope of the problem and the answer as
to what is the prime value that ought to
be governing our response to plague and
pandemic is actually I don't think it
would be to Socrates it's not obvious
and the fact that we've taken it as
presumptive that it is obvious is a
fascinating thing to begin with and I
think it's actually without claiming to
know the answer to the question it's
frightening to totally well this is just
a gift just to give some so as usual
we've been talking you know all day
before if we press record but I was just
to fill everyone in or what we're
talking about so there we were talking
about coalbed and the response to curve
in and I was kind of telling Chris a
story about that oh this is one thing
about that I didn't quite think of when
I was watching an interview were
somebody brought up that there's a
precedent set that wasn't supposed to be
possible which is the world basically
came together basically through
government like like democratic systems
for the most part and paused economy
caused all the things about production
paused all of the all of the things that
make the world go round and Koba didn't
do that right it was it was a decision
made across the world and so this guy
was pointing out like oh whoa that's the
first time the whole that hold man the
mania of the market right was able to
actually stop and and dramatically stop
and then you know all these consequences
and then Chris asked me well what do you
actually think about that like look what
happens in you I was like well I don't
you know I add my own response and and
Chris was like any hot when he said it I
realized that I was in the affect of it
as well because I hadn't seen
this which was basically he's gone
unquestioned that health right in the
threat to physical life ready our
physical I went on a question that we're
gonna stop everything right and the
whole world stopped as if as if you've
been health right was the most important
thing basically was on top of the here
over here close to it close enough to it
and you're not saying that that that
shouldn't be the case right that's not
what's being said here it's saying that
that it's the case and then that is kind
of like assumed that that's the gap and
yeah yeah I guess I was assuming that
too and I and I've had my moments of
assuming that as well and I think many
people whose first reaction was to
immediately fear for the well-being of
the lives of somebody that they loved it
was easy to default to that of course it
was easy to devote to that and and and
such as the such as the such as the
power and imminence and immediacy of
that reaction that it actually takes a
fair degree of I think philosophic
effort to even playfully even as an
exercise dissociate from that
perspective long enough to see it as
though from outside of it I was talking
to I had a really great chat with
Sevilla King yesterday we were talking
about this for a while and talking about
this in the language of piercings
qualities metaphysicians of quality
static quality versus dynamic quality
which i won't i won't retrace here
because it was a great conversation in
its own right but i think the that the
thing that the thing that has has become
more and more obvious to me is precisely
that it is not obvious philosophically
it is not at all obvious to me that the
health of the body is the prime value
the prime superordinate avalue around
which to organize a relationship to
reality and our relationship to one
another and our relationship to the
world Socrates would not have drank the
hemlock yeah right is
such a thing were obvious right we've
been reading these platonic we haven't
read the Phaedo yet but we've been
reading we've started reading these
Platonic dialogues and there's a pretty
punctuating point at the end of the
Phaedo woo that the health of the body
at least for Socrates right the
enclosure of his sensible reality was
not ultimate enough when weighed against
the life and health of his soul so his
preparation for death was was ultimately
more important now I'm not saying that
the health of the body is somehow not
important or that you know I'm not this
isn't an enjoined ER or an injunction to
- you know what I mean I don't know I'm
not professing to know but to me I think
I like precisely to not know I am
professing to not know and I'm
professing to have noticed and not just
on my own but in conversation with you
and with John and with other people you
know some other very very good friends
of mine that I've been talking to about
this certainly not not autonomously you
know not as some kind of divine
revelation but in conversation with
people
yeah I'm professing to have noticed yeah
that there is a certain presumption a
certain implicit presumption an
axiomatic one that we've all
collectively made that has that has
halted something that most of us did not
believe could be halted yeah in a matter
of weeks so really powerfully like
really powerfully yeah and it is it has
it has alluded itself as such an obvious
and presumed axiom that it has gone so
unquestioned and to me I think we need
to look at that very very closely
because there's something very powerful
about it we you you you and I were
saying you were saying there's something
incredibly impressive about the fact
that this could happen so expeditiously
yeah but at the same time especially
when we're talking about these implicit
axiomatic perspectives that we live
within and therefore cannot see there's
something incredibly unnerving and even
about that presumption especially when
for the better part of you know the last
no no 2500 years or so we've had a lot
of sagacious people canonically telling
us that there is something eternal about
the human being that is precisely not
confined yeah to the health of the body
right I'm not in you don't need to
subscribe to the transmigration of the
soul in order to believe that right and
that's not not making any kind of
supernatural claims at all but within
our lived within the ontology of our
lived and felt existential experience
right you know the philosopher is aware
that there is a great deal more to the
life lived right the unexamined life
right
so anyway there's there's something very
there's something about the fundaments
of that presumption and how quickly and
how unthinkingly I think it was that is
really a cause for for a cause for a lot
of things a cause for attention first of
all maybe a cause for concern maybe a
cause for Kairos if we're all very lucky
I don't know
but well well just the story that
interests me and all of this totally
well one it's just like what's
interesting to me is it there can be cuz
I mean that the Spanish flu was what
1916 or something like that right yeah
yeah one for one yeah yeah like just
didn't you just look at plagues and Wars
and everything like that like I mean it
definitely hasn't just been assumed
right that's that physical health is
like the the end-all ray or the the
measure upon which to do try to
sacrifice almost everything so I'm just
I'm at one obstruct that that is just
assumed right this is part of this is
what's what's interesting about being in
a secular culture is that you can't
really be in a secular culture it just
means that like you know in in a
Christian like a medieval Christian town
now I'm not a Christian right but it but
it's almost as if I'm Western it's
almost impossible we do not be yeah yeah
you are and you're not yeah yeah but
there's a if you look at like if you
look at medieval towns the highest that
are still preserved in the originals you
know for four years the highest point is
is that is the church right it's the
across everything when you look up
everything's organized
everything's explicitly about that right
so there was no I mean back then there
was no question about what what the
hell's on top right now I could have the
experience of not noticing what's on top
right exactly
that's uh yeah wild exactly exactly as
beautifully put guy and a time like this
a time like this froze that into
distinction because a time like this
calls attention on unwitting kind of
attention to what is on top and and yeah
that's right you know the steeple is no
longer at the top of the village right
because because a because of because of
paradigm founded on the symbolism of
self-sacrifice and suffering is is not
philosophically consonant with the
principle that the health of the body is
the highest good right right now of
course we've talked ad nauseam about the
fact that we're facing we're in the
throes of a time where that is where
that is that's in declension right
that's in that's in that of course that
that values has been eroded over the
course of time and that's precisely the
point of the meaning crisis right is
that we've lost we've lost our converse
with the life of the Spirit and
therefore the life of the body can be
can be elevated to divine status in its
stead yeah yeah that's right that's
right but I think it's it it it there's
a great deal of attention to this the
particular state of the soul to the
particular nature of our our spiritual
predict
our response to covet I think is deeply
deeply symptomatic in ways that we have
really yet to fully understand because
we're still in it and we're still having
very instinctual understandably we're
still having very instinctual reactions
to it right we're where we want to self
preserve enough but I think that well
self what we call what is worth
preserving right is so oh good yeah
so one thing you know it's just kind of
like I you know that's one of the things
I love about reading history right and
philosophical esther ii all that stuff
is that you you realize that there was
one point with what what is so itself
evidently obviously true to you now was
not always true right and and you get
that you get the his historical miss
infinitude of your own self evident
truths about what's going on through
reading history right like you get a
glimpse it like the you know the the non
infinite way that you've been not
noticing that you've been taking reality
so it's kind of there's this quality of
them like things like what we call
reality things at what we call a self
what we call deeming worthy of sacrifice
like all of those things yeah it's so
interesting to me to think about that
that that it's one of the crisis's right
I think of the meaning crisis is that
there's no there's no place to show
these note there's no real with any kind
of weight anymore right there's no
institution or place that reveals the
top of the thing that we're looking at
to guides like this right now there's
but like you know Hegel and all these
people you know the the the age of
reason
you know modernism comes from its let
like it definitely exposed that there's
it's not like that that's heaven right
that like you get in all kinds of
problems with that but at the same time
when you remove that it
we still act religiously and this is
kind of like what I think one of the
things that you're talking about right
is like oh yeah there's a way in which
we just don't even question it yeah yes
yes well then that very that very
dissonance is its own it's is then its
own performance of despair right the
fact that we still act as if we still
act still act religiously even though we
are less and less concentred by a a
model of the self that in that that that
that uh finds us to a relationship with
a self beyond it right yeah so the self
that's I loved what you said like the
self that the self that is being
preserved in in rushing to stress
rushing to occlusion rushing to
sequestering is not the self that is
preserved as Socrates drinks the hemlock
right the self that Socrates is
preserving by drinking the hemlock is
not the self that we they're preserving
by refusing to drink the hemlock yeah
yeah and I'm not obviously again that's
not like that that's that's not that's
not cuz I'm we have at you know
advocating recklessness right but you
know what I mean yeah totally yeah well
definitely like I don't think you know
Socrates wasn't recklessly drinking no
no like he was that was an active yes
before it was suck about that for a
second so it's like for him to make that
choice right in the face of that he
basically was saying what what do you
think well how would you put what he was
basically saying what was the thing that
was more important than his is physical
going on this oh man
oh man how much do I want to this
up guy how much do I want to it up
as much as possible using Socrates it
spare its paradox all the way down on
some level yes yes I think that there is
a I think that that there is a so
there's so many things happening at the
same time there's so many things
happening at the same time yeah but but
what there is something gestural and you
know illusions and comparisons to Christ
and the sacrifice of Christ or perhaps
appropriate but I'm certainly not brave
enough to venture into them right now
but there again there's something about
that and I and I say gesture
analogically right the jet that the
sacrificial gesture right the sacrifice
of the body the logos of that gesture is
a logos that embodies possibility
outside of its bounds right it's like
taking a deep lungful of what a deep
proleptic lungful of what is knowingly
beyond the scope of your being and
because is it it is it is knowingly
beyond the scope of your being it
necessarily must be that which
rearranges your values as they try as
they attempt to regather themselves
around it hmm right so the sacrificial
gesture is somehow a kind of embodied a
kind of embodied and a logic
toward that which is knowingly more than
the imminent values around which your
reality is currently organized right and
you know how can you be how can you be
fully accommodative of that reality it's
it's you can't write precisely because
it's beyond you right so you have to be
as Socrates was as the lover right
suspended between ignorance and wisdom
and when the ignorance becomes knowing
then then then it can start to
appreciate an agog eclis precisely
because it realizes that its confines
its confines entailed the presence of
the very thing that it's that it's
constituted by which is more of itself
and more than itself yeah at the same
time right the more than itself is also
the more of itself right in the way that
the life because a Gustin has this
distinction between the life of the body
and the life of the source or I'm
bouncing around like all hell here is
deciding between pasty white Socrates
drink the head yeah so it's oh you're
fighting done just rhetoric race I'm
Augusta has this and I think if I
understand it right it's quite possible
they don't but he has a sensation
between you know the life of the body
and the life of the soul and the life of
the body I think what he means by the
life of the body is not the body itself
right but it's the animation of the body
it's the body as it as the body presence
is the life of the soul which is that
the the you know the aspect of self that
exists over beyond itself right some
something like that exists in the anima
Mundi right in the Neoplatonic
hypostasis right so we're constituted by
that which is fundamentally beyond us
fundamentally fundamentally transcended
to us and but because we're constituted
by it we we also we are refined with its
properties right and so the body the the
the life of the body the
life of the body becomes the embodied
enacted analogy for the intelligibility
that is beyond the body right that's why
the in pragmatics of gesture yeah are so
much more encompassing of speech of the
word Lagos right the meaning of logos as
the word the pragmatics the pragmatics
of the semiosis of the body and its
ability to perform semiosis because it's
there's a sense in which you use
gestures right to to help the surplus of
a meaning that can't be put into just
the word right so your gesturing yeah
it's funny it's interesting that's right
that's right so it's it's like striking
it's like developing developing a
conversant between the life of the body
and the life of the soul right which is
to say the the the being by which the
but the being by which the being in body
is constituted and that conversant which
can only be called proleptic or a matter
of faith is something that we only know
but to use to use the language that we
use and to use John's language right it
can only unknown in participation right
can be known in gnosis and participatory
knowing which is my the which is why the
pragmatics of ritual are so essential to
its semiosis because it's an embodied
performance of patterns of
intelligibility that it cannot fully
accommodate but that it partakes of even
though it's partaking of them is ever
and always
insufficient hmm hmm so there is
something so Chi didn't bring in it way
back there is something in there is
something not only in the logos of
Socrates speech as he dialogues with his
friends in the moments before taking the
hemlock but there is a deep and profound
dramaturgy to his actual imbibing of
that unlock as a way of embodying the
very analogous that he has been
developing his converse with with his
friends
in the moments and hours you know
preceding his death right it's the
preparation for death right anyway that
so yeah I don't know and in short I have
no idea yeah in short I have no idea
yeah but that's that's quite hell of a
no idea like well it's quite a hell of
him well you you you had this look
beautiful you you had this beautiful
little you had this this I keep trying
to remember it it was I'm gonna I'm
gonna butcher it but you had you had you
were you we were talking earlier we've
been talking for a long time leading up
to this particular moment but at one
point you said you know our our
interaction with unknown such that it
let never loses its unn yeah right and
so something like that it still remains
only it's silver remains profoundly
unknown to me but perhaps um perhaps
more more more appreciated or more
appreciable and it's unknown missed
right that's the best best we can do and
that's the thing I mean that's the
property of logos right the probability
of logos has the unit of discourse and
it's connection to the more cosmic
definition of logos right the logos is
the unity of the you the unifying
principle of reason that binds the
cosmos and continuity that what connects
one of those definitions to the other
this is this is part of what I've been
thinking about and part of the work and
doing that John but it's like it's am
autonomous the logo says the word and
the logo says the cosmic reason it's a
meta it's a it's a it's a metonym one is
a metonym for the other it's a
metronomic relationship metonymic it's
the nimac relationship which is to say
that one is a much abbreviated what one
is a much abbreviated semiotic gesture
for the other and and I think that's why
do logos is so profound because what do
logos does is it animates the gesture of
so that it appreciates its own ignorance
and insufficiency so that that ignorant
becomes a knowing form of ignorance that
develops a relationship a kind of a kind
of animate rapport with everything it
gestures to and yet does not encompass
if that makes right tiny iota
this is where you put your you know I'm
just thinking about my dad's you know
bump bumper sticker coffee cup a phrase
you know that he always talks about like
that you know also sorry you cut it you
cut out for me for a second what say
that again what was like that when my
dad used to always decoding my dad says
all all human suffering you can boil
down to where where where man puts a
period where God put a question mark
right oh yeah yeah yeah the sensitive
there is the sentient with Swift with
these dialogues there is this sense in
which you're always left aware of that
you have been like both of and not yet
found to something that isn't quite
formed but in a but but in a an aspiring
aspiration with it right it's really
embodied right and so just yes so just a
sense of like you know on some level
think about just think about this is
just stunning to think about right so to
to basically we just basically have
stopped the world right voluntarily
pretty much because something was unlike
something was a period and it wasn't
even it wasn't even it wasn't even
it's not even like it's not even seen as
a period right upon which we didn't
notice that we're just having as the
ultimate value right which is you know
physical you know our physical mortality
you know um
you know he start to think about that
like well well one it makes a lot of
sense in terms of all of the work on on
transhumanism right on I'm trying to
break that code and you know on some
level of like that well if that's the
hot top of the hierarchy we got some
work to do oh that's a good point right
like that's a good point is this a good
for that because if that's the top of
the hierarchy right and that's the thing
that that's the end we can't have that
be the end which makes so much sense
because if so if if if the health of the
body if the Wellness of the body got
wellness that the word the word drives
me absolutely crazy wellness when if
health and wellness is a new kind of new
old has been around for a while yeah
kind of Orthodoxy yeah then the tread
that makes the transhumanism movement a
kind of neo Gnosticism interesting
interesting sit by an analogy and by
analogy so like if because you know
because the I mean the Gnostics were
many things but but one of one of which
was was was a form of a form of a form
of transgressive heresy to the orthodoxy
right so fused with the belief that that
personal cultivation could was
sufficient to transcend the boundaries
of enclosure that the orthodoxy was
otherwise was otherwise a proponent of
to some degree right it's a breaking
through the ceiling as it were breaking
through the perforating the canopy yeah
and so I mean the the trends humanism
movement seems so intuitively stunted in
its particular aims that seems so unwise
intuitively for so many reasons but but
what you say makes a lot of sense that
if you know health and wellness is a new
form of a pseudo religiosity a pseudo
religious kind of orthodoxy that is has
is revealed quite dramatically
the moment held aloft as being of prime
an ultimate value then the idea that
that it's superable the idea that
physical limitations or you know
mortality superable in the form of
technological appendices you know
appendages and other things is I think
analogous to have to uh to to a kind of
Gnostic belief that that what was that
that that the boundaries that the
proffered boundaries are in fact
superable insofar as they've been
presented to us by an orthodoxy that
that hope that you know that holds them
intact yeah anyway it's it's it's a very
imperfect analogy but but it's what
occurred to me when you said that I
hadn't thought of it in that way before
right right because it's like what it I
guess what if we if we look at this is
just that it's just amazing it's like
fascinating to think about this you know
I I think this is actually what's what
well is what's the kind of stuff that's
worthy of thought is is that you haven't
been thinking right it's like so go
ahead it Kyogre said you know that you
know what is worthy of thought today
what is most worthy of thought today is
that you haven't yet begun thinking you
really get absolutely absolutely
absolutely and there's a dead one so so
why did exactly you know so on one level
it's physical device right that seems to
be the thing that was worth stop and
everything right unquestionably the
health of the body ensuring the health
of the body be kind of the top of it now
what's interesting about that is what is
that reveal about what we view as the
body right by definition it's kind of
like the body is is that which dies
right it it's kind of like that's what
kind of makes it a body not a rock or
something it's case it it's it's finite
on some level like there is this
we're what sits at the top is by
definition almost it's it's it's its end
right but like not an end is beyond it's
like the end like what does it say both
like what we call physical body do we
really mean like when we refer to the
physical body what does it mean to have
that be a god right what are we actually
conceiving of it when we don't notice
that we're conceiving of it as a
particular way what is the body what is
health all these kinds of things right
um and to is like what does it mean
right to have it there what does it mean
to have it there so interesting to think
that and have that be the organizing
context yeah if if we're if if the if
what we're playing with here I want to
emphasize playing right and right and
what and what then does it imply yeah
what then does it imply yeah if it's
something that is something who's
perhaps most incommensurable property is
finitude yeah is then invested with the
divinity of infinitude right yeah is
what we what we sacrifice for that it's
like it's really interesting
I mean it's um
because there's something about like
what I think about this is there's
something about like the the way so much
process I don't know this is quite the
connection but the way that like so like
in technology for example in the
technological way of being I'll say
right not necessarily technology but
like what what makes something
technological and you know bringing
Heidegger here about where talks about
like well we are in the age where the
understanding of that which is is a
technological understanding meaning that
um it we say it's real and it is it bees
to the degree that it's a it's a
position to define two other positions
and in frames them right so it's a madam
eating system yeah totally so it's like
we're we're it's more it's more of the
sense of what you are what I am with
everything that is by virtue of which it
is isn't the understanding of that is
that that which is that which can be
exploited optimized utilized right
extracted that's the thing about
technology so it's not like it's not
like a windmill produces electricity
you'd if you think about a little
windmill right there's a way in which
for the windmill it it it you know the
wind it uses the wind right to propel
the thing to create electricity but it
doesn't it keeps the wind intact and
partakes it yeah it partakes of the wind
if anything it partakes of it but it
doesn't possess it right yeah it
animates it articulates in some way
that's why it's kind of beautiful to
think of a windmill right like right it
is animated by it yeah yeah yeah yeah
yeah well what do you think about it for
example nuclear energy which is way more
technological actually it breaks apart
nucleons right so there's this kind of
quality where it's not it's not
gathering and partaking in something
it's extracting something it's changing
something out of it yes
energy right yes it's like yes it's
sucking it out and that what yes and
what's crazy about that well anything
about it is like one is that it's our
understand with Heidegger's correct
right about this if we kind of follow
his notion of it I am - you are -
everything that is right that we can
call is shows up and his is based on
virtue of which the understanding of
which is that it is a resource yeah
bodies is a resource right like
physicality is a resource like let's in
in this it's interesting because you
think about like the whole thing and I'm
I mean I love this stuff but like like
mind hacking this notion of body hacking
kind of this kind of sense of like where
there is a position there's a like a
turn this used to be really fringe and
now this is you you can see it more and
more and more and more present
we're just referring to the body is a
resource that you have yeah right yeah
and again hacking to me hacking also
once again a buck yes yeah once again
evocative oh Gnosticism to me hacking
hacking finding the secret code finding
the secret intervention interesting into
with narcissism the shadow of narcissism
right where where you would say
Gnosticism loses its way if you will
right because it was like a rip like
that there's also Gnosticism which is
you know brilliant oh absolutely yeah I
just mean yes yes there's a there's a
way in which you can invoke it with deep
deep reverence in sapiens I I yes it's
true I'm using a particular critical
right taking yeah yeah exactly taking a
particular instance of it critically in
just do I want to play with that sit for
a second so with Gnosticism because I
I'm not I still have a hard time kind of
getting my head around when Gnosticism
really is but um the if it's connected
in the way that right the good side of
Gnosticism for lack of a better term
what's going on in Gnosticism
that makes it connected and considerate
of the whole right versus the the shadow
side of it what is the difference that
makes that difference well I certainly
don't pretend for an instant to be an
expert my understanding of it my
understanding my understanding of the
Gnostic quest insofar as its wisdom is
concerned it's precisely that it is
chiefly concerned with an agog a right
the Gnostic quest is the ANA gaagaa
quest fundamentally if I was to like
very crudely distill it down to a
particular property a particular value
it would be an ax GOG a an Agha gaze the
Gnostic quest it's it's a kind of divine
ascension it's the it's the it's that's
its climbing the Platonic ladder as it
were it's the it's the it's the it's the
appreciating affinity of the person to
their divine aspect such that such that
they become more in likeness to their
divine nature and so become more
enlightening itself it is the apotheosis
project right yeah that's my my
understanding of it but the thing is
that I mean that's and that I think we
could very comfortably equate with the
notion of gnosis itself and so far as
you know than the kind of gnosis that
the neo platonic sense of gnosis that
we've discussed sin many of these
dialogues I think that the more critical
use of the term Gnosticism and what John
and I have talked about in terms of neo
Gnosticism is that the mythos that the
cosmology of Nossa Senhora I'm talking
about Gnosticism as though it's somehow
one unified movement and of course
that's not true it's distributed and
it's endlessly varied in its forms so I
don't mean to talk about it you Niva
Klee it's not univocal but they're but
the the
the cosmologies around Gnosticism that
have to do with incarceration by the
Demiurge it force that kind of that that
keeps us in clues that keeps us up you
skated that keeps our keeps us blind to
reality those cosmologies are are richly
cast with all kinds of characters and
narratives that in in in i think in the
modern context wit would manifest as a
kind of deeply conspiratorial thinking
and so when we used so the term neo
Gnosticism i think in the way that that
john and i use it it has it has much to
do with v the casting forth of
conspiratorial narratives as a way of
explaining the anomalous nature of a
poetic experience or inter categorical
experience right so that when something
happens like this right like the koba
situation that brings everything to a
halt and starts to untie tectonic lee
Underminer models of reality one's
instinct or one reaction to it just as
it has been you know erstwhile for the
meaning crisis as a whole is to foist
this maria with a series of narratives
attempting to account for the sudden
vacancy that has opened beneath us yeah
and that you know that the the
projecting of an alternate narrative to
try and reclass reforge unity and
coherence out of something that has
fundamentally lost its unity and lost
its coherence and so that attempt just
as the transhumanism is right that it's
tempted kind of somehow forcibly insert
some kind of intervention to make sense
of a sudden finitude a set of an you
know a sudden gap a sudden a sudden a
sudden loss a sudden sense of loss is
something that we might describe as a
form of neo Gnosticism interesting
interesting so the cell phone closedness
great
of Gnosticism right of mmm it's kind of
kind of a form of idolatry it sounds
like on some level like idolatry it
certainly certainly can be yeah yeah I
think so
I think that it can be that sense in
which so I guess you know what another
way that we could look at it is playing
with this again of like like okay so
what the top is like there's an idolatry
of the body of physicality that's even
specifically it's even sort of cementing
Hanabi right yeah oh it has I mean it
has decisively its decisively surpassed
economy that's the whole point
yeah and it's decisively surpassed you
know sociability and it's decisively
surpassed all kinds of things right in
the in the current in the moment yeah
and I and I think you know again even as
I say it I feel her Etica land
transgressive because of course how
could you how could you question like I
feel guilty even for saying it and I
want to be attentive to that reaction as
I say you know the hell that the
apotheosis Asian of the body
yeah is a kind of idolatry yeah and then
someone might say well Chris don't you
want to be healthy like of course I do
of course I do don't you want your
family to be healthy of course I do
but there's a heresy immediate heresy
yes yes healthy for the sake of in
service of even that just like having
health as it end exactly
and there's the unexamined life yeah
question again right yes health and
service of put like
I think I'd Northrop Frye has a has a
getting back to this idea the logos the
metonymy of logos and its relationship
to the greater logos the logos of more
nests as john has has been calling it is
that you know there's a difference
between something an identity
relationship and metaphor as an identity
relationship this is that or a metonymic
relationship which is this is put for
that hmm this is put for that so to me
the life of the body the health of the
body is put for yeah a value that is
beyond it
right it is put for a value that is
beyond it and and and that is precisely
the opposite of idolatry right that's
the difference between the idolatrous
the idolatrous individual at the Apostle
writes the Apostle is put for the put
you know put put in service of what is
fundamental of what is constitutive of
it and what is also beyond it guy I'm
sorry I just have to be attentive I'm
running a bit bit tight on time so I
think I might have to I
that's we didn't get to reading Plato
but we did dance around and written here
yeah we we hit recording in the last
like what last half-hour of a
conversation we talked for we'll totally
so yeah okay my friend let me done sorry
stop record